cockroachlabs.com 2019-06-26

# Privacy

## Privacy Policy

_Last Revised: February 6, 2019_

Cockroach Labs, Inc. (“ **CRL** ,” “ **we** ,” or “ **us** ”) provides this privacy policy (the “Privacy Policy”) to explain how we collect, use and disclose personally identifiable information (“ **Personal Information** ”) about you when you visit or use any of the websites owned or operated by CRL (collectively, the “ **Sites** ”), any of our products or services that you can access, download, or use via the Sites (collectively, the “ **Services** ”), or when you otherwise interact with us. By visiting or using the Sites or any of our Services, you consent to our collection, use, disclosure, and processing of your information as described in this Privacy Policy. Please note that this Privacy Policy does not apply to any third-party websites, services, products, or applications, even if they are accessible through our Sites or the Services.

We may change this Privacy Policy from time to time. If we make changes, we will notify you by revising the date at the top of this Privacy Policy, adding a statement to our homepage, by sending you an email, and/or by some other means. Please note that if you’ve opted not to receive legal notice emails from us (or you haven’t provided us with your email address), those legal notices will still govern your use of the Services, and you are still responsible for reading and understanding them. If you use the Services after any changes to the Privacy Policy have been posted, that means you agree to all of the changes. We encourage you to review this Privacy Policy periodically to stay informed about our practices.

We do not knowingly collect or solicit Personal Information from anyone under the age of 13. If you are under 13, please do not attempt to use the Services or send any Personal Information about yourself to us. If we learn that we have collected Personal Information from a child under age 13, we will delete that information as quickly as possible. If you believe that a child under 13 may have provided us Personal Information, please contact us at [info@cockroachlabs.com](mailto:info@cockroachlabs.com).

#### Information We Collect

##### Information You Provide to Us

We collect any Personal Information that you give us. For example, we collect Personal Information about you when you sign up for one of our Services, create an account, participate in any interactive features of the Sites or the Services, fill out a form, give us feedback, ideas or submissions about any of the Services, communicate with us via third party social media sites, request customer support, register for white papers, web seminars, and other events hosted by us, or otherwise communicate with us via the Sites, the Services, or any other means.

The types of Personal Information we may collect include your name, email address, credit/debit card information, as well as any other Personal Information you choose to provide to us. For information about ways to limit our collection of your Personal Information, please see the “ **Account Information** ” section below. If you choose not to provide certain Personal Information, you understand that we may not be able to provide certain of our Services to you, and that certain features of our Sites or Services may be unavailable or work differently.

##### **Personal Information We Collect Automatically When You Use the Sites or the Services**

When you access or use the Sites or use the Services (or certain portions of the Sites or Services), we automatically collect certain Personal Information about you. This information includes:

**Log Information** : We log Personal Information from your use of the Sites and the Services, including the type of device you use, access times, IP address, pages viewed, and the page you visited before navigating to one of our Sites and/or using the Services. We use this information for analytics and product improvement purposes.

**Device Information** : We collect Personal Information about the computer or device you use to access the Sites and the Services, including the hardware model, operating system and version and unique device identifiers. We use this information for analytics and product improvement purposes.

**Information Collected by Cookies and Other Tracking Technologies** : We use various technologies to collect Personal Information, including cookies and web beacons. Cookies are small data files stored on your hard drive or in device memory, while web beacons (also known as “ **tracking pixels** ”) are non-visible electronic images. These technologies are used for analytics and product improvement purposes, such as seeing which areas and features of our Sites and Services are popular, or determining whether an email has been opened and acted upon. For more information about cookies, and how to disable them, please see the “ **Cookies** ” section below.

**Information Collected From Other Websites and Do Not Track Policy** : Through cookies we place on your browser or device, we may collect information about your online activity after you leave our Services. Just like any other usage information we collect, this information allows us to improve the Services and customize your online experience, and otherwise as described in this Privacy Policy. Your browser may offer you a “Do Not Track” option, which allows you to signal to operators of websites and web applications and services (including behavioral advertising services) that you do not wish such operators to track certain of your online activities over time and across different websites. Our Services do not support Do Not Track requests at this time, which means that we collect information about your online activity both while you are using the Services and after you leave our Services.

#### Personal Information We Collect From Other Sources

We may obtain Personal Information about you from other sources, and combine that with information we collect through your access and use of our Sites and the Services. For example, if you create or log into your account through a site like Google.com or GitHub.com, we may have access to certain information about you from those sites, such as your name, log-in credentials, account information, and friends lists, in accordance with the authorization procedures determined by those sites. We may receive Personal Information about you from other sources like telephone or fax, or from companies that provide our products and services by way of a co-branded or private-labeled website or companies that offer their products and/or services on our website (“ **Third Party Companies** ”). Our Third Party Companies may supply us with Personal Information, such as your calendars and address book information, in order to help us establish the account. We may add this information to the information we have already collected from you via our website in order to improve the products and services we provide.

##### Personal Information We Collect Automatically When You Use the Sites or the Services:

  * Provide, deliver, maintain, test and improve our Sites and Services;
  * Send you technical notices, updates, confirmations, security alerts and support and administrative messages;
  * Respond to your comments, questions, and requests, and to provide customer service;
  * Communicate with you about products, services, offers, promotions, rewards and events offered by CRL and others, and to provide news and information that we think may be of interest to you;
  * Monitor and analyze trends, usage and activities in connection with our Sites and Services;
  * Detect, investigate and prevent suspected breaches of the terms applicable to your use of our Sites and Services; and
  * Link or combine with information we get from others to help understand your needs, and to provide you with better service.

CRL does not use your Personal Information for purposes that are materially different from the purposes described above, unless you otherwise authorize us to do so.

Additionally, we collect and use de-identified information about your usage of the Services through diagnostic reports in order to help us understand and improve the Services. For more information about diagnostics reporting (including how to opt-out), please visit <https://www.cockroachlabs.com/docs/stable/diagnostics-reporting.html>.

##### How We Share Your Personal Information

We may share your Personal Information with third parties as described in this section.

**Information that’s been de-identified:** We may de-identify your Personal Information so that you are not identified as an individual, and provide that information to our partners. We may also provide aggregate usage information to our partners (or allow partners to collect that information from you), who may use such information to understand how often and in what ways people use our Services, so that they, too, can provide you with an optimal online experience. However, we never disclose aggregate usage or de-identified information to a partner (or allow a partner to collect such information) in a manner that would identify you as an individual person.

**Public Profiles** : If you choose to create a profile and post in any forums or discussion boards on the Sites, other visitors to the Sites may be able to see certain Personal Information in your profile, such as your username, profile picture, and any content that you submit or post.

**Agents and Service Providers** : We may share your Personal Information with vendors, consultants and other service providers who need access to such information to perform work or provide services on our behalf. These third parties will only have access to your Personal Information as necessary to perform their functions, and may not use your Personal Information for any other purpose.

**Analytics Services** : We may use third parties to provide analytics services in connection with the Sites or Services (or portions of the Sites or Services). These entities may use cookies, web beacons and other technologies to collect information about your use of the Sites and Services, including, among other things, your IP address, web browser, pages viewed, time spent on pages, links clicked and conversion information. We may use this information to, among other things, analyze and track data, determine the popularity of certain content, personalize the user experience, and better understand your activity.

We also use Google Analytics to collect information about the Services and your use of the Services in order to understand how our Services are operating and to improve the Services. If you would like more information on how Google uses data when you use the Services, please refer to the “How Google uses data when you use our partners’ sites or apps” section of Google’s policies, located at www.google.com/policies/privacy/partners/.

**Business Transfers** : We may choose to buy or sell assets, and may share and/or transfer customer information in connection with the evaluation of and entry into such transactions. Also, if we (or our assets) are acquired, or if we go out of business, enter bankruptcy, or go through some other change of control, Personal Information could be one of the assets transferred to or acquired by a third party. In addition, we may disclose Personal Information in connection with the evaluation of and entry into a financing with respect to CRL. We may also share your Personal Information between and among CRL and our current and future parents, affiliates, subsidiaries and other companies under common control and ownership.

**Compelled Disclosures** : We may disclose your Personal Information to government or law enforcement officials or to private parties as we, in our sole discretion, believe necessary or appropriate to:

  1. respond to claims and/or legal process (including subpoenas);
  2. to protect the property and/or rights of CRL or any third party;
  3. to protect the safety of the public or any person;
  4. to prevent or stop any illegal, unethical, or legally actionable activity;
  5. to comply with applicable law or regulation; or
  6. in response to any lawful request by public authorities, including, without limitation, to meet national security or law enforcement requirements.

**Protection of Us and Others** : We may also share your Personal Information as needed to enforce our terms of use with respect to the Sites or the Services and/or to protect the rights, property and safety of CRL or others.

Finally, we may share Personal Information with your consent or at your direction, including if we notify you through any of the Services that the information you provide will be shared in a particular manner, and you choose to provide such information.

##### Security

Your account is protected by a password for your privacy and security. If you access your account via a third party site or service, you may have additional or different sign-on protections via that third party site or service. You must prevent unauthorized access to your account and Personal Information by selecting and protecting your password and/or other sign-on mechanism appropriately and limiting access to your computer or device and browser by signing off after you have finished accessing your account.

CRL is committed to safeguarding the confidentiality of your Personal Information. As part of that commitment, we take reasonable administrative, physical, and electronic measures to help protect your Personal Information from loss, the, misuse, unauthorized access, disclosure, alteration or destruction. Please be aware, however, that no method of transmitting information over the Internet or storing of information is completely secure. Accordingly, we cannot guarantee the absolute security or secrecy of any of your Personal Information.

##### Account Information

You can review, amend, correct, or delete certain Personal Information such as your username, profile picture, email, and password, by accessing your password-protected account page. If you want us to delete information relating to any of your accounts on your behalf, please email us at support@cockroachlabs.com with your request. Note that we may retain certain information as required by law, or for business reasons as we deem necessary to fulfill the purposes identified in this Privacy Policy. We may also retain cached or archived copies of your information (including location information) for a certain period of time. The information you can view, update, and delete may change as the Services change. If you have any questions about viewing or updating information we have on file about you, please contact us at info@cockroachlabs.com.

##### Cookies

Most web browsers are set to accept cookies by default. If you prefer, you can usually choose to set your browser to remove or reject browser cookies. Please note that if you do choose to remove or reject cookies, this could affect the availability and functionality of the Sites and certain of the Services.

If you would like to update your cookie settings you can do so by clicking the settings button below.

##### Promotional Communications

You may opt out of receiving promotional communications from CRL by following the instructions in those communications. If you opt out, we may still send you non-promotional communications, including those relating to your current accounts or your use of the Services.

##### Links to Other Sites

Our Sites and Services may contain links to other websites, including those of our advertisers and partners. If you choose to visit another website by clicking on an advertisement, hyperlink, or otherwise, you will be directed to that third party’s website. The fact that we link to a website is not an endorsement, authorization or representation of our affiliation with that third party. We do not exercise control over third party websites. These other websites may place their cookies or other files on your computer, collect your data, or solicit personal information from you. This Privacy Policy only addresses the use and disclosure of information that we collect from you through our Sites and Services. Other websites may follow different rules regarding the use or disclosure of the information you submit to them. We encourage you to read the privacy policies or statements of other websites you visit, before providing your information to them.

##### Opting Out

CRL does not disclose your Personal Information to third parties, other than to third parties that act as our agents and service providers to perform tasks on our behalf and pursuant to our instruction as described above (collectively, “ **Processors** ”) that relate specifically to making our products and services available to you. We enter into contracts with each of our Processors. You will not be able to opt out of such disclosures, since those Processors are operating on our behalf and at our instruction in order to help make our products and services available to you. You do have the ability to opt out of receiving promotional communications, by following the instructions in those communications; see the “ **Promotional Communications** ” paragraph above for more information. You also have the ability to opt out of having your web browsing information used for behavioral advertising purposes; see the “ **Analytics Services** ” paragraph above for more information.

CRL does not use your Personal Information for purposes that are materially different from the purpose(s) for which that data was originally collected.

#### Contact Us

If you have any questions or concerns about this Privacy Policy or any privacy issues, please email us at: [info@cockroachlabs.com](mailto:info@cockroachlabs.com).
